[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]
So we've made a small change to the gradient algorithm but it is still big.
لقد قمنا بإجراء تغيير بسيط على خوارزمية التدرج لكنها ما زالت كبيرة.
We start looking at all the data points one at a time.
نبدأ بالنظر إلى جميع نقاط البيانات كل على حدة.
Why should this even work?
لماذا يجب أن يعمل هذا؟
Why is this a good idea at all?
لماذا تعتبر هذه فكرة جيدة على الإطلاق؟
Let's spend a little bit of time getting intuition of why it works.
دعونا نمضي قليلا من الوقت لفهم الحدس وراء عملها.
And this intuition is going to help us understand the behavior of
وسوف يساعدنا هذا الحدس في فهم سلوك
the algorithm in practice.
الخوارزمية عند الممارسة.
In this picture, I'm showing you the landscape,
في هذه الصورة، أريكم المشهد،
the counter plot for our sentiment analysis problem,
التخطيط المقابل لمشكلة التحليل العاطفي،
which is the data that we'll be using throughout our module today.
وهي البيانات التي سنستخدمها طوال الوحدة اليوم.
But just for a subset of the data where we're only looking at two possible
ولكن فقط لمجموعة فرعية من البيانات حيث نبحث فقط في اثنتين من الميزات الممكنة
features, coefficient for awful and the coefficient for awesome.
معامل "سيء" ومعامل "جيد".
And if we were to start here at this point,
وإذا كنا سنبدأ هنا من هذه النقطة،
this would be the exact gradient that would compute.
سيكون هذا هو التدرج المضبوط الذي نحسبه.
And that exact gradient gives you the best
ويمنحك هذا التدرج الدقيق أفضل تحسن ممكن
possible improvement of going from wt to wt plus one.
من الوزن wt إلى wt زائد واحد.
That's the best thing you could possibly do.
وهو أفضل ما يمكن فعله.
Now, there are many other directions that also improve the value,
الآن، هناك العديد من الاتجاهات الأخرى، التي تعمل أيضًا على تحسين القيمة،
improve the likelihood, the quality.
أو تحسين الاحتمالية والجودة.
So for example, if we were to take this other direction over here and
إذن، على سبيل المثال، إذا كنا سنأخذ هذا الاتجاه الآخر هنا
we reached some parameter w prime is still okay.
سنصل إلى المتغير w prime ما يزال الأمر جيدًا.
Because it is still going uphill we're increasing the likelihood.
لأنه ما زال صاعدًا، وبالتالي يزيد من احتمالية ذلك.
In other words,
بمعنى آخر،
the likelihood of w prime is going to be greater than the likelihood of wt.
واحتمالية w prime ستكون أكبر من احتمالية wt.
So in fact, any direction that take uphill will be good
بل إن أي اتجاه متصاعد سيكون جيدًا
the gradient is just the best direction.
والتدرج هو أفضل اتجاه.
The gradient direction is the sum of the contributions for
اتجاه التدرج هو مجموع المساهمات
each one of the data points.
لكل نقطة من نقاط البيانات.
So, if I look at that gradient direction.
فإذا نظرت إلى هذا الاتجاه المتدرج.
It is the sum over my data points of the contributions for each one of these xis.
هو مجموع نقاط البيانات للمساهمات لكل واحدة من xis.
So this is the, each one of these red lines here are the contributions from
فكل واحدة من هذه الخطوط الحمراء هنا هي المساهمات من
a data point,
نقاط البيانات
from each
كل
xiyi, which is this part of the equation, here.
xiyi، وهو هذا الجزء من المعادلة هنا.
So interestingly, most contributions point upwards.
من المثير للاهتمام أن معظم المساهمات تشير إلى الأعلى.
So, all of these over here are pointing in an upward direction.
فكل هذه الأشياء هنا تشير إلى الاتجاه الصعودي.
So if I were to pick any of those, I would make some progress.
وإذا ﻛﻧت ﺳﺄﺧﺗار أي منها، ﺳﺄﺣرز ﺑﻌض اﻟﺗﻘدم.
If I picked any of the other ones, like the ones back here,
إذا اخترت أيًا من الأخرى، مثل تلك الموجودة هنا،
this would not make progress, this would be bad directions.
فلن يتم إحراز التقدم، وبالتالي فهي اتجاهات سيئة.
But on average, most of them are good directions.
لكن في المتوسط، معظمها اتجاهات جيدة.
And this is why stochastic gradient works.
وهذا هو السبب في عمل التدرج العشوائي.
In stochastic gradient, we're just going to pick one of these directions.
من خلال التدرج العشوائي، سنختار واحدًا من هذه الاتجاهات.
And most of them are okay.
ومعظمهم على ما يرام.
So most of the time, we're going to make progress.
وبالتالي في معظم الأوقات، سوف نحرز تقدمًا.
Sometimes when we take a bad direction, we won't make progress.
في بعض الأحيان عندما نتخذ اتجاهًا سيئًا، لن نحرز أي تقدم.
We'll make negative progress.
بل سنحرز تقدمًا سلبيًا.
But on average, we're going to be making positive progress.
لكن في المتوسط، سنحرز تقدمًا إيجابيًا.
And so, that's exactly why stochastic gradient works.
وهذا هو بالضبط السبب في عمل التدرج العشوائي.
So if you think about the stochastic gradient algorithm,
فإذا فكرت في خوارزمية التدرج العشوائي،
we're going one data point at a time.
سنتعامل مع نقاط البيانات كل على حدة.
And picking the direction associated with that data point and
واختيار الاتجاه المرتبط بنقطة البيانات تلك
maybe taking a little step.
ربما من خلال تدرج بشيط.
So, at first iteration we might pick this data point and make some progress and
لذا، في البداية، قد نختار نقطة البيانات هذه ونحقق بعض التقدم
the second one make this number too here and make negative progress.
أو نختار الثانية هنا ونحرز تقدمًا سلبيًا.
But in the third one, I pick another one that makes positive progress and
لكن في الحالة الثالثة، أختار واحدة أخرى تحقق تقدمًا إيجابيًا
I pick a fourth one that makes positive progress.
واختر رابعة تحقق تقدمًا إيجابيًا.
And I pick a fifth one that doesn't and I pick a sixth one that does and so on.
واختر خامسة لا تحقق تقدمًا، واختر سادسة تحقق تقدمًا وما إلى ذلك.
And so, most of the time we're making positive progress and
ولذلك، في معظم الأوقات، نحرز تقدمًا إيجابيًا
overall the likelihood is improving.
كما تتحسن الاحتمالية بشكل عام.
[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]